Guide to the Brooklyn Navy Yard oral history collection ARC.003
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Oral History Interview with Howard Zinn, 2008 2008; December 8, 2008; 2010.003.041
  During his interview, Howard Zinn (1922-2010) explains how he ended up working at the Brooklyn Navy Yard and details his work there as an apprentice shipfitter. He says the best part of his time at the Navy Yard was organization the Apprentice Association, which was an organization of apprentices who were not allowed to be a part of the American Federation of Labor unions at the Yard. He also talks about his salary, organizing a basketball team, commuting to work from Fort Greene, uniforms, witnessing a workplace accident, and race and ethnicity. Interview conducted by Daniella Romano.
  Warships; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Labor |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Ethnicity; Apprentices; Accidents; Public housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Wages |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Shipfitting; Work environment |z New York (State) |z Kings County; World War, 1939-1945; New York Naval Shipyard
- Oral History Interview with Carmela Zuza, 2008 2008; July 3, 2008; 2010.003.001
  Carmela Celardo Zuza (1924- ) grew up in Crown Heights and Bedford-Stuyvesant, Brooklyn, with eight siblings. Her parents moved to the United States from Naples, Italy after they were married. Carmela worked in small factory jobs before she began working at the Brooklyn Navy Yard in 1942 as an arc welder.
  In her interview, Carmela Zuza (1924- ) discusses her experience growing up in an ethnically diverse neighborhood in Brooklyn. She describes in detail the garden that her parents kept, the beer and wine her parents made, and other local foods. She expresses the pride she felt doing her work at the Brooklyn Navy Yard and seeing the christening of the USS Missouri battle ship. Zuza also talks about transportation to and from work, security at the Brooklyn Navy Yard, discrimination, uniforms and clothing for women, gender relations, social activities and dating. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
  Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Dean Street (New York, N.Y.); Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Washington Avenue (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Sands Street (New York, N.Y.); African American women; Dating (Social customs); Cranes, derricks, etc; Ethnicity; Friendship; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Local transit; Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Work environment |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Wages |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Shipyards |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Shipfitting; Shipbuilding |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Women |x Employment |z New York (State) |z Kings County; World War, 1939-1945; Gardens; Family life; Welding; Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; New York Naval Shipyard; Missouri (Battleship: BB 63); Franklin (Aircraft carrier)